A Guide to the New River Valley Planning District Commission Records, 1959-1991, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
New River Valley Planning District Commission Records, 1959-1991, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1998-024
3.0 cu. ft. 3 boxes
The New River Valley Planning District Commission records consist of reports, files, and other literature gathered and used by the commission to aid their planning for the New River Valley of Virginia.
New River Valley Planning District Commission.
Adminstrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The New River Valley Planning District Commission Records were donated to Special Collections in December 1998.
Historical Note
The New River Valley Planning District is one of twenty one planning districts in Virginia whose commissions are chartered under Virginia law. Also known as PDC 4, the organization encompasses the counties of Floyd, Giles, Montgomery, and Pulaski, and the City of Radford.
The commission serves the local governments in the area and their citizenry by providing a number of different services ranging from economic development to regional recycling. The purpose of the planning district commission is to promote regional cooperation, to coordinate the activities and policies of member local governments, and to provide planning assistance to local governments. The commission is financed by a combination of local, state, and federal funds.
Information from the "About New River Valley Planning District Commission" website: http://www.nrvpdc.org/aboutpdc.html
NRVPDC homepage: http://www.nrvpdc.org/index.html
Scope and Content
The New River Valley Planning District Commission records consist of reports, files, and other literature gathered and used by the commission to aid their planning for the New River Valley of Virginia. Some of the records, spanning from 1959 to 1991, deal with forestation, wilderness management, water systems, economic concerns, and housing in the New River Valley and other areas of southern Appalachia. Also includes several publications from the Appalachian Regional Commission.
Arrangement
Materials in the collection are in chronological order, with undated items at the end.
Index Terms
Local Subjects:
Local/Regional History
Contents List
- Bulletin of VPI, Geology and Mineral Resources of Floyd County, 1959. (Box-folder 1-1 to 1-2 (2 folders))
- Public Law 86 - 577, 88th Congress S.4, 1964. (Box-folder 1-3)
- Economic Activity Areas in Appalachia Pennsylvania, 1969. (Box-folder 1-4)
- Summary of Changes in Volume 25 of the Appalachia Report, 1969. (Box-folder 1-5)
- Report for Development of Water Resources in Appalachia, 1970. (Box-folder 1-6)
- Planning Advisory Service, Manual, January 1970. (Box-folder 1-7)
- Unit Plan Number One, Poverty Creek, Jefferson National Forest, Blacksburg Ranger District, 1971. (Box-folder 1-8)
- Planning Advisory Service, Reports Numbers 276, 268, 1971. (Box-folder 1-9)
- Planning Advisory Service, Reports Numbers 269, 270, 1971. (Box-folder 1-10)
- Planning Advisory Service, Reports Numbers 272, 273, 274, 1971. (Box-folder 1-11)
- Information sent to State Representatives from the Appalachian Regional Commission, 1972-1973. (Box-folder 1-12)
- ARC, Development Directory, 1972-1973. (Box-folder 1-13)
- Appalachian Regional Commission Appropriations, 1972-1973. (Box-folder 1-14)
- Information sent to Commission Members from the Appalachian Regional Commission, 1972-1973. (Box-folder 1-15)
- Department of Housing and Urban Development, Improvement of Costs, 1972. (Box-folder 1-16)
- Annual Report of the Appalachian Regional Commission, 1972. (Box-folder 1-17)
- Planning Advisory Service, Report Numbers 278, 281, 1972. (Box-folder 1-18)
- Planning Advisory Service, Report Numbers 282, 283, 1972. (Box-folder 1-19)
- Planning Advisory Service, Report Numbers 284, 285, 286, index, 1972. (Box-folder 1-20)
- Planning Advisory Service, Report Numbers 287, 288, 289, 290, 1973. (Box-folder 1-21)
- Planning Advisory Service, Report Numbers 292, 293, 1973. (Box-folder 1-22)
- Health Continuation Burden Summary, Fiscal Year 1973, 1973. (Box-folder 1-23)
- Planning Advisory Services, Reports Numbers 295, 296, 297, 1973. (Box-folder 1-24)
- Summary of Actions taken at Commission Meeting, 1973. (Box-folder 1-25)
- Planning Advisory Services, Reports Numbers 298, 300, 302, 304, 1974. (Box-folder 1-26)
- Virginia’s Development Strategy, Appalachian Region, Preliminary Draft, 1974. (Box-folder 1-27 to 1-28 (2 folders))
- Public Law 93_662, 93rd Congress S.3433, 1975. (Box-folder 1-29)
- Appalachian Regional Commission Project Preparation Guidelines, 1975. (Box-folder 1-30 to 1-31 (2 folders))
- Consulting Engineering, A Guide for the Engagement of Engineering Services, 1975. (Box-folder 1-32)
- Planning Advisory Services, Memos, 1976. (Box-folder 1-33)
- Report Number 329; Index of Planning Advisory Service Projects, 1977. (Box-folder 1-34)
- Planning Advisory Service Memos, 1977. (Box-folder 1-35)
- Planning Advisory Service Memos, 1978. (Box-folder 1-36)
- Best Management Practices Handbook, Agriculture, 1979. (Box-folder 1-37 to 1-38 (2 folders))
- Planning Advisory Service Memos, 1979. (Box-folder 1-39)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, Annual Implementing Investment Program, 1979. (Box-folder 1-40)
- Appalachian Regional Commission Annual Report, 1979. (Box-folder 1-41)
- Planning Assistance Bulletins, 1979-1982. (Box-folder 1-42)
- Development Strategy for the Appalachian Region of Virginia, 1978. (Box-folder 1-43)
- Development Strategy for the Appalachian Region of Virginia, 1978. (Box-folder 2-1)
- Housing Innovation Handbook for Appalachia, 1980. (Box-folder 2-2 to 2-3 (2 folders))
- Appalachian Regional Commission Boundary, 1980. (Box-folder 2-4)
- Planning Advisory Service Memo, 1980. (Box-folder 2-5)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, Research on the Cost of Public Services, 1980. (Box-folder 2-6)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Index 1949-1980, 1980. (Box-folder 2-7)
- Appalachian Settlement Patterns Study, Final Report, 1981. (Box-folder 2-8)
- Letter Regarding the Cool Springs Public Water System in Pulaski County, 1982. (Box-folder 2-9)
- Approved Projects, Appalachian Regional Commission, 1981. (Box-folder 2-10)
- Information Relating to the New River Valley Planning District Commission Budget, 1982. (Box-folder 2-11)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, Materials for the July 28, 1982, meeting, 1982. (Box-folder 2-12)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, Materials for the February 2, 1983, meeting, 1983. (Box-folder 2-13)
- Appalachia, Journal of the Appalachia Regional Commission, 1983. (Box-folder 2-14)
- Public Law 98-586, Oct. 30, 1984, 98th Congress, 1984. (Box-folder 2-15)
- Seventeenth Annual Report, Kentucky Area Development District, 1985. (Box-folder 2-16)
- Annual Report, Appalachian Regional Commission, 1985. (Box-folder 2-17)
- Draft, Virginia Agricultural Access Network Pilot Study; Final Report, 1985. (Box-folder 2-18)
- Annual Report, Appalachian Regional Commission, 1986. (Box-folder 2-19)
- A Call from the Wilderness, 1986. (Box-folder 2-20)
- Breaking New Ground in the New Development, 1986. (Box-folder 2-21)
- New River Valley Planning District Commission, Semi-Annual Progress Report, draft, 1986. (Box-folder 2-22)
- ARC Budget- first draft and total, 1986-1987. (Box-folder 2-23)
- Semi Annual Progress Report, April 1, 1987- September 30, 1987, 1987. (Box-folder 2-24)
- Best Management Practices for Forestry, 1988. (Box-folder 2-25)
- Appalachian Regional Commission Development District Directory, 1988. (Box-folder 2-26)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, 1988. (Box-folder 2-27)
- Annual Report, Appalachian Regional Commission, 1990. (Box-folder 2-28)
- New Acquisitions List, Geology Library, VA Tech March-June, 1991. (Box-folder 2-29)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 305, 306. (Box-folder 2-30)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 307, 308. (Box-folder 2-31)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 311, 312. (Box-folder 2-32)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 314, 315. (Box-folder 2-33)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 322, 323. (Box-folder 2-34)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 317, 318. (Box-folder 2-35)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 319, 321. (Box-folder 2-36)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 324, 325, 326, 327. (Box-folder 2-37)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 330, 331, 332, 333. (Box-folder 2-38)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 334, 335, 336. (Box-folder 2-39)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 338, 339. (Box-folder 2-40)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 342, 343, 344. (Box-folder 2-41)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 345, 346, 347, 348. (Box-folder 2-42)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 353, 355, 356, 357. (Box-folder 2-43)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 358, 359, 361, 362. (Box-folder 2-44)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 363, 364, 365. (Box-folder 2-45)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 367, 368, 369. (Box-folder 2-46)
- Planning Advisory Services, Report Numbers 370, 371, 372. (Box-folder 2-47)
- Appalachian Regional Commission Administrative Grant Application. (Box-folder 3-1)
- Poverty Creek Plan Number 1. (Box-folder 3-2)
- Special Business Report for the National Business Incubation Association. (Box-folder 3-3)
- Unit Plan for the Management of Poverty Creek Unit. (Box-folder 3-4)
- Fiscal Year 1981 Project Package. (Box-folder 3-5)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, Part One, Organization, Administration. (Box-folder 3-6)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, Part Two, Policies, Programs, Procedures. (Box-folder 3-7)
- Best Management Practices Handbook, Forestry. (Box-folder 3-8)
- President’s Appalachia Regional Commission. (Box-folder 3-9)
- Research Management, Notes numbers 5-8. (Box-folder 3-10)
- Discussion Paper on ARC Evaluation Strategy. (Box-folder 3-11)
- Geologic Map of Floyd County, VA. (Box-folder 3-12)
- Planning Advisory Service, Report Index, 1949-1982. (Box-folder 3-13)
- Planning Advisory Service, Memos numbers m-1, m-3, m-4, m-6, m-7, m-8, m-11, m-12. (Box-folder 3-14)
- Housing Innovation Handbook, Innovative Houses; Resource Organizations and Activists. (Box-folder 3-15)
- Housing Innovation Handbook; National and Regional Resource Organizations. (Box-folder 3-16)
- Housing Innovation Handbook; Bibliography. (Box-folder 3-17)
- New River Valley Economic Development Alliance, Rules and Procedure. (Box-folder 3-18)
- New River Valley District Commission By- Laws. (Box-folder 3-19)
- The Need for Wilderness Management Philosophical Direction. (Box-folder 3-20)
- Roadless Area Evaluation. (Box-folder 3-21)
- The Need to Develop Wilderness Management Direction. (Box-folder 3-22)
- Concerns and Issues for the State Wide Groups at the Wilderness Conference. (Box-folder 3-23)
- Draft Issues and Concerns for the Wilderness Committee to spend time on. (Box-folder 3-24)
- Prescription for Management Area Number 3. (Box-folder 3-25)
- Summary of the Unit Plan for Managing the Upper Craig Creek Unit. (Box-folder 3-26)
- A Proposal, Mill Creek Wilderness. Draft Environment Impact Statement. (Box-folder 3-27)
- Pen and Ink Changes for Volumes 6-10; Explanatory Note for Volume 12. (Box-folder 3-28)
- Housing Innovation Handbook for Appalachia. (Box-folder 3-29)
- Housing Innovation Handbook; Housing Technology Briefs. (Box-folder 3-30 to 3-31 (2 folders))
- Program Policy Statement. (Box-folder 3-32)
- Housing Innovation Handbook for Appalachia, ARC. (Box-folder 3-33 to 3-34 (2 folders))
- Appalachian Regional Commission. (Box-folder 3-35 to 3-36 (2 folders))